Guide to the Frances Logan Merriam papers 1948-1972
Montana Historical Society
Frances Logan Merriam Papers
1948-1972
Montana Historical Society Archives
MC 58
Merriam, Frances Logan 1899-
10.2 linear feet of shelf space
Frances Merriam (b. 1899) served as the Executive Secretary of the Committee for Paradise Dam, an organization that promoted the construction of the Paradise and Knowles dams in western Montana. Papers (1948-1972) consist primarily of subject files and correspondence concerning the dams and her work in the Montana Democratic Party.
Frances Dummer Logan Merriam was born December 24, 1899, in Chicago, Illinois. She was the daughter of William and Ethel Dummer. Frances Dummer attended Francis W. Parker High School in Chicago, graduating in 1917. She entered college at the University of Wisconsin, where she received Phi Beta Kappa honors, and graduated in 1921. Following graduation from college, Frances Dummer taught school for three years in San Diego, California, 1921-1924. In 1926, she was awarded a diploma as a psychiatric social worker from the New York School of Social Work. Shortly thereafter, she returned to her home state and was employed for ten months at the Illinois Institute for Juvenile Research. She continued her work in education while working in the Winnetka, Illinois, public schools as an education counselor, 1926-1931. While employed there, she met and married Simon Rae Logan, then Assistant Superintendent of Schools. The Logans continued living in Winnetka, while raising a son, Francis, and a daughter, Katharine. Mrs. Logan later served as a co-director of the Chicago Metropolitan Council of Civil Defense (Chicago Council of Social Work), 1942-1946. In 1946, when her husband retired, Frances Logan moved with him to a farm/homestead near Charlo, Montana. She remained active in political life, serving as Montana's First District Democratic Congressional Committeewoman, 1962-1964. For three years, she also served as the state's Democratic National Committeewoman. Frances Logan was also a charter member of the Committee for Paradise Dam, an organization that promoted the construction of Paradise and Knowles Dams in western Montana, in 1957, and later served as its Executive Secretary, 1959-1965. Her husband died in 1970, and in 1974 she married Harold G. Merriam, University of Montana English professor emeritus.
The majority of the materials reflect Frances Logan's work as the executive secretary of the Committee for Paradise Dam. Included are subject files containing correspondence, reports, clippings, publications, and miscellany; clippings; and testimony from hearings presented before various congressional committees. These materials are included in the Paradise-Knowles Dams subgroup. The remaining papers are general correspondence (primarily with Lee Metcalf), and subject files relative to Frances Logan's work in the Montana Democratic Party, 1955-1972.
Arranged by subgroup and series. Some material housed in oversize folder in archives map case. See inventory below for more information.
Collection open for research.
Acquisition information available upon request
Photographs and selected printed material were transferred from this collection to the M.H.S. Photo Archives and Library respectively.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the Montana Historical Society Archives catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search under these terms.
Merriam, Frances Logan 1899-
Buffalo Rapids Project (Mont.); Charlo (Mont.); Hells Canyon Dam (Idaho and Or.); Hungry Horse Dam (Mont.); Kerr Dam (Mont.); Knowles Dam (Mont.); Libby Dam (Mont.); Oregon--Industries; Paradise Dam (Mont.); Paradise Irrigation District (Mont.)
Dams--Montana; Electric Power--Montana; Electric Utilities--Law and legislation--Montana; Federal Government; Indians Of North America--Government relations; Irrigation--Montana; Political parties--Montana; Public utilities--Regulation--Montana; Salish Indians; Salish Indians--Politics and government; Columbia River Treaty (1961); Rural electrification--Montana
Montana
Detailed Description of the Collection
The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection
- Frances Logan Merriam
  - General Correspondence
    - A (correspondents include LeRoy Anderson, Murl Axtell), 1957, 1966 (Box-folder 1 / 1)
    - Confederated Salish and Kootenai Tribal Council, 1957-1964 (Box-folder 1 / 2)
    - C-E (correspondents include Leo Carmody, Committee for Paradise Dam, Chester City Mayor, Gardner Cromwell, Suzanne Emmons), 1958-1968 (Box-folder 1 / 3)
    - Flathead Irrigation Project, 1962-1965 (Box-folder 1 / 4)
    - F-L (correspondents include Dorothy Floerchinger, Elmer Freshour, Horace Gray, Harold Gunderson, Averill Harriman, Jerry Holloron, Indian Affairs, KLCB Libby, Ann Low), 1956-1969 (Box-folder 1 / 5)
    - Donna Metcalf, 1958-1971 (Box-folder 1 / 6)
    - Lee Metcalf, 1955-1972 (Box-folder 1 / 7-19)
    - Missoulian [primarily letters to the editor], 1957-1972 (Box-folder 1 / 20)
    - Montana Farmers Union, 1957 (Box-folder 1 / 21)
    - Montana Rural Electric News, 1957-1962 (Box-folder 1 / 22)
    - Montana State Board of Health (re air and water pollution, includes article "Stream Waste Disposal and Public Health in Montana," by G.D. Carlyle Thompson, 1961-1968 (Box-folder 1 / 23)
    - M (correspondents include Mike Mansfield, Gary Marbut enclosing statement to Montana Water Pollution Control Council, Allen McAlear, Montana Power Company, James E. Murray), 1957-1967 (Box-folder 1 / 24)
    - M (correspondents include National Congress of American Indians, National Farmers Union, Northwest Public Power Association), 1957-1963 (Box-folder 1 / 25)
    - People's Voice (Harry and Gretchen Billings), 1957 (Box-folder 1 / 26)
    - P-R (correspondents include Donald A. Paddock, The Plainsman, Miles Romney), 1957-1962 (Box-folder 1 / 27)
    - Adlai E. Stevenson, 1955-1956 (Box-folder 1 / 28)
    - S-W (correspondents include Alvin E. Sloan, Cy Tonner, U.S. Bureau of Indian Affairs, U.S. Federal Power Commission, U.S. House Appropriations Committee, U.S. Rural Electrification Administration, U.S. President's Water Pollution Control Commission), 1957-1968 (Box-folder 1 / 29)
    - Unidentified, 1961, 1964 (Box-folder 1 / 30)
  - Subject Files
    - Air pollution, 1966-1971 (Box-folder 2 / 10)
    - Confederated Salish and Kootenai Tribal Council minutes, 1957, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 2 / 2)
    - Flathead Irrigation Project (includes land ownership lists, crop reports, contracts, legislation, circular letters, clippings, etc.), 1962-1971 (Box-folder 2 / 3-4)
    - Indians (includes House Subcommittee on Indian Affairs hearing, Hellgate Treaty, petition, Char-Koosta, Kicking Horse Conservation Center, clippings), 1955-1970 (Box-folder 2 / 5-6)
    - Indians: termination of tribal ownership of land, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 2 / 7)
    - Montana Air Pollution Advisory Council, 1967 (Box-folder 2 / 8)
    - Montana-Idaho Assembly on State Legislatures in American Politics, 1966 (Box-folder 3 / 1)
    - Montana Power Company (includes reports to stockholders, clippings, etc.), 1957-1972 (Box-folder 3 / 2-6)
    - Montana Power Company: advertisements, 1963-1970 (Box-folder 3 / 7)
    - Montana Power Company: natural gas, 1961-1965 (Box-folder 3 / 8)
    - Montana Water Pollution Council (includes public hearing on proposed revision of water quality standards, clippings), 1967-1968 (Box-folder 3 / 9)
    - Municipal utilities, 1967 (Box-folder 4 / 1)
    - Newspapers, 1957-1971 (Box-folder 4 / 2)
    - Overcharge (re publication of book by Lee Metcalf), 1967 (Box-folder 4 / 3)
    - Water pollution (includes clippings, report on "The Anaconda Company Waste Treatment Plant for the Butte Mines and Anaconda Reduction Works", stream classifications, federal legislation, etc.), 1963-1970 (Box-folder 4 / 4-5)
- Committee For Paradise Dam
  - Subject Files
    - Advertising, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 5 / 1)
    - Amendments to Congressional bills, 1957-1960 (Box-folder 5 / 2)
    - American Public Power Association correspondence, 1957-1963 (Box-folder 5 / 3)
    - Annual meeting, 1959 (Box-folder 5 / 4)
    - Articles of incorporation, bylaws, etc., 1957-1961 (Box-folder 5 / 5)
    - Articles and publications, 1958, 1962 (Box-folder 5 / 6)
    - Audits and financial statements, 1957-1963 (Box-folder 5 / 7)
    - John F. Baldwin (R. Calif.) questionnaire [includes question on Knowles Dam], 1963 (Box-folder 5 / 8)
    - Beets (includes statistics of sugar beet growing), 1957-1966 (Box-folder 5 / 9)
    - Mondell Bennett correspondence, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 5 / 10)
    - Roy F. Bessey correspondence and testimony, 1960-1965 (Box-folder 5 / 11-12)
    - Bills (re Knowles Dam alternative to Paradise Dam, Yellowtail Dam, Hells Canyon Dam; also includes report on "Multiple-Purpose Storage Possibilities, Clark Fork River Basin"), 1953-1960 (Box-folder 5 / 13)
    - Bills (re Knowles Dam and Paradise Dam; statements of Gus Norwood, Roy F. Bessey, David R. Brower, S.R. Logan; clippings), 1957-1960 (Box-folder 6 / 1-2)
    - Harry and Gretchen Billings correspondence, 1965-1971 (Box-folder 6 / 3)
    - Bio-degradable products, 1964 (Box-folder 6 / 4)
    - Bison (primarily re effect of Knowles Dam on National Bison Range), 1961-1965 (Box-folder 6 / 5)
    - Board of Directors correspondence, 1957-1964 (Box-folder 6 / 6-7)
    - "Brainwash" (see also: Advertising), 1957-1962 (Box-folder 6 / 8)
    - British Columbia Hydro Takeover (re takeover of British Columbia Electric Company by government), 1961-1963 (Box-folder 6 / 9)
    - Buffalo Rapids (re proposed Montana Power Company dams: includes correspondence, Federal Power Commission applications, clippings, etc.), 1958-1968 (Box-folder 6 / 10-12)
    - Buffalo Rapids / Kerr Dam (re proposed Confederated Salish and Kootenai Tribes and Montana Power Company joint project for dams at Buffalo Rapids and re-licensing of Kerr Dam), 1961-1966 (Box-folder 6 / 13-15)
    - Businessmen (re appeal to businessmen to support Paradise Dam), 1957-1959 (Box-folder 7 / 1)
    - Canadian diversion and projects (re proposals to divert water from upper Columbia River to Fraser River; also Peace River Project), 1958-1963 (Box-folder 7 / 2)
    - Canadian-United States Columbia River Treaty, 1958-1963 (Box-folder 7 / 3)
    - Leo Carmody correspondence (Central Montana Electric Generation and Transmission Cooperative), 1963 (Box-folder 7 / 4)
    - Cattle (list of number of head of cattle owned by Little Bitterroot Valley ranches), 1963 (Box-folder 7 / 5)
    - Henry P. Caulfield correspondence (U.S. Dept. of Interior), 1962-1963 (Box-folder 7 / 6)
    - Chambers of Commerce (correspondence with Chambers of Commerce in area where dams have been built, including Glasgow and Polson), 1955-1966 (Box-folder 7 / 7)
    - Chelan [Wash.] Public Utility District, 1957 (Box-folder 7 / 8)
    - Christian Century article and response to it by S.R. Logan, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 7 / 9)
    - Ed Christopherson correspondence, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 7 / 10)
    - Earl Chudoff correspondence, 1957 (Box-folder 7 / 11)
    - Citizens Committee Against Knowles, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 7 / 12)
    - Coal (re coal-fired electric generating plants), 1965-1966 (Box-folder 7 / 13)
    - Columbia River Regional Corporation bill (drafted by Northwest Public Power Association), 1958 (Box-folder 7 / 14-16)
    - Columbia Valley Authority flyer, 1947 (Box-folder 7 / 17)
    - Committee for Paradise Dam (includes circular letters, meeting notices, speeches, flyers, correspondence, clippings, etc.), 1957-1959 (Box-folder 7 / 18)
    - Clifford Davis correspondence, 1963 (Box-folder 7 / 19)
    - Deficit (re financial deficit of Committee), 1957 (Box-folder 7 / 20)
    - Democratic Party platform letter on Paradise Dam, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 7 / 21)
    - Displaced persons (re protection for people displaced by highways and dams), 1958-1962 (Box-folder 7 / 22)
    - Floyd E. Dominy correspondence (commissioner of Bureau of Reclamation), 1961 (Box-folder 7 / 23)
    - Downstream Benefits bill, 1959-1961 (Box-folder 8 / 1)
    - Leonard B. Dworsky correspondence (Columbia Basin Inter Agency Committee), 1961-1962 (Box-folder 8 / 2)
    - Dwight D. Eisenhower (speeches and press releases re power projects), 1955-1961 (Box-folder 8 / 3)
    - Election results (letters to Mike Mansfield, James E. Murray, and LeRoy Anderson re significance of support to Paradise Dam), 1958, 1960 (Box-folder 8 / 4)
    - Executive Committee (includes lists, circular letters, mail ballots, hearing statements), 1965-1966 (Box-folder 8 / 5)
    - Expenses, 1959-1965 (Box-folder 8 / 6-7)
    - Federal Power Commission (includes act, rules and procedures, planning status report on Clark Fork-Pend Oreille River Basin, "Hyrdoelectric Power Resources of the United States", clippings, correspondence, opinions), 1955-1968 (Box-folder 8 / 8-10)
    - Flood damage (re value of dams for flood control purposes), 1957-1967 (Box-folder 8 / 11)
    - Foundation study (includes "Outline for Study of Research and Planning Program and Organization for the Paradise Project Area, and of Requirements for Outside Financial and Technical Assistance Therein" by Roy F. Bessey), 1957-1958 (Box-folder 8 / 12)
    - John Garber correspondence, 1957-1963 (Box-folder 8 / 13)
    - Ferris G. Gilkey correspondence (manager, Bonneville Power Administration, Kalispell District Office), 1962-1963 (Box-folder 8 / 14)
    - Ernest Gruening correspondence (re The Public Pays), 1959-1960 (Box-folder 8 / 15)
    - Hanford Reactor (re use of surplus nuclear power to generate electricity), 1961-1963 (Box-folder 9 / 1)
    - Paul Harlow correspondence, speeches, etc., 1957-1970 (Box-folder 9 / 2)
    - Hells Canyon Dam (Snake River, Idaho), 1957-1959 (Box-folder 9 / 3-4)
    - Jerome Hewankorn correspondence (re his petition calling for election on Confederated Salish and Kootenai Tribe agreement with Montana Power Company re-licensing Kerr Dam), 1965-1967 (Box-folder 9 / 5)
    - Hungry Horse Dam (primarily clippings), 1948-1968 (Box-folder 9 / 6)
    - Leon Hurtt correspondence (includes report "Big, Little, and Medium Sized Dams on the Upper Columbia R."), 1957-1962 (Box-folder 9 / 7)
    - Indians (includes Confederated Salish and Kootenai Tribal Council minutes, hearing testimony, circular letters, etc.), 1957-1960 (Box-folder 9 / 8)
    - Industrial News Review article against Knowles Dam and Lee Metcalf response to it, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 9 / 9)
    - Kerr Dam rental from Confederated Salish and Kootenai Tribe by Montana Power Company (includes Federal Power Commission decision readjusting rate), 1966-1967 (Box-folder 9 / 10)
    - Knowles Dam correspondence, 1957-1963 (Box-folder 9 / 11)
    - Knowles Dam correspondence, 1958-1964 (Box-folder 10 / 1)
    - Knowles Dam letters to Congress, 1962 (Box-folder 10 / 2)
    - Knowles Dam mass mailings, 1960-1965 (Box-folder 10 / 3)
    - Knowles Dam testimony, 1962 (Box-folder 10 / 4)
    - Labor support for Paradise Dam, 1957 (Box-folder 10 / 5)
    - Lake County membership activities, 1957 (Box-folder 10 / 6)
    - Land acquisition (re protections for land owners), 1957, 1961 (Box-folder 10 / 7)
    - "Land Grab" hoax (re Bureau of Reclamation application for withdrawal of lands needed for Knowles Dam from appropriation for other purposes), 1963 (Box-folder 10 / 8)
    - Legislative history (includes various versions of bills, reports, correspondence, clippings, etc.), 1956-1964 (Box-folder 10 / 9)
    - Legislative Joint Memorial #1 (re Paradise Dam), 1957 (Box-folder 10 / 10)
    - Letterhead (includes permissions from all members of board of directors to appear on letterhead), 1963 (Box-folder 10 / 11)
    - Letters to editors [mostly undated, no order], 1957-1965 (Box-folder 10 / 12-13)
    - Libby Dam (includes correspondence, circulars, clippings, ground-breaking ceremony), 1956-1966 (Box-folder 11 / 1)
    - Charles F. Luce correspondence (Bonneville Power Administration), 1961-1971 (Box-folder 11 / 2)
    - Harvey McPhail correspondence (Kuljian Corporation), 1959 (Box-folder 11 / 3)
    - Mike Mansfield correspondence, 1957-1964 (Box-folder 11 / 4)
    - Michael Mapes (Special Counsel to Senate Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs: includes memos to James E. Murray and Mike Mansfield, reports, etc.), 1956-1967 (Box-folder 11 / 5)
    - Maps (includes sketch maps of sites, section drawings for dams and spillways, contour map of Paradise Dam, drainage map of Clark Fork and tributaries) [some maps in OVERSIZE FOLDER], 1948-1957 (Box-folder 11 / 6)
    - Miscellaneous Maps [Map Case], 1948-1957 (Oversize-folder 1)
    - Mass mailings (re both Paradise and Knowles dams), 1957-1962 (Box-folder 11 / 7)
    - Membership (includes correspondence, lists, contributions, etc.), 1957-1965 (Box-folder 12 / 1-7)
    - Lee Metcalf correspondence, 1957-1961 (Box-folder 12 / 8-9)
    - Lee Metcalf correspondence, 1962-1965 (Box-folder 13 / 1-2)
    - Minutes of executive board and membership meetings, 1957-1965 (Box-folder 13 / 3)
    - Moiese Bison Range (includes list of employment of opponents to dam), 1963 (Box-folder 13 / 4)
    - Howard Morgan correspondence (Federal Power Commission), 1963 (Box-folder 13 / 5)
    - Motel owners (circular letters), 1963 (Box-folder 13 / 6)
    - Municipal ownership of electric power, 1959-1961 (Box-folder 13 / 7)
    - James E. Murray correspondence, 1957-1960 (Box-folder 13 / 8-9)
    - Robert W. Nelson correspondence (U.S. Dept. of Interior), 1962-1966 (Box-folder 13 / 10)
    - Richard Neuberger speeches and clippings, 1957 (Box-folder 13 / 11)
    - Northwest Public Power Association correspondence, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 13 / 12)
    - Northwest Public Power Association correspondence, 1957-1961 (Box-folder 14 / 1)
    - Northwest Public Power Association: Spokane conference, 1964 (Box-folder 14 / 2)
    - Northwest Public Power Association: Gus Norwood correspondence and clippings, 1959-1965 (Box-folder 14 / 3-7)
    - Oil drilling (re filing of options on land to be flooded near Moiese), 1957-1958 (Box-folder 14 / 8)
    - Arnold Olsen correspondence, 1957-1963 (Box-folder 14 / 9)
    - Opposition to Paradise Dam, 1957-1960 (Box-folder 14 / 10)
    - Partnership (re proposals to sell power from public dams to private utilities), 1957-1960 (Box-folder 15 / 1)
    - Bill Pickett correspondence, 1963 (Box-folder 15 / 2)
    - Policy statements, 1958, undated (Box-folder 15 / 3)
    - Population study (lists of occupied and unoccupied houses in dam area), 1959-1963 (Box-folder 15 / 4)
    - "Pork Barrel" article in Life magazine and responses to it, 1963 (Box-folder 15 / 5)
    - Press (includes press releases, clippings, etc.), 1957-1965 (Box-folder 15 / 6-8)
    - Truman Price correspondence (Washington State Dept. of Conservation), 1963 (Box-folder 15 / 9)
    - Quotes and scripts, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 15 / 10)
    - Relocation (re relocation of rail lines and people required for Paradise Dam), 1957-1961 (Box-folder 15 / 11-13)
    - Roland Renne (includes "Green Gold: Montana's Undeveloped Water Resources"), 1959-1960 (Box-folder 15 / 14)
    - Reprints and quotes, 1953-1959 (Box-folder 15 / 15)
    - Review report (re Columbia River 308 Review Report), 1958-1960 (Box-folder 16 / 1)
    - Michael A. Rivisto correspondence, 1960 (Box-folder 16 / 2)
    - Nita G. Robbin correspondence, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 16 / 3)
    - Russia's river development, 1957-1960 (Box-folder 16 / 4)
    - Steel mill (re proposed steel mill at Anaconda), 1959-1960 (Box-folder 16 / 5)
    - Benton J. Strong correspondence (staff member Senate Interior and Insular Affairs Committee; includes "Report on Resources on the New Frontier", 1961-1962 (Box-folder 16 / 6)
    - Sugar company (re American Crystal Sugar Company and its relationship to Anaconda Company, Montana Power Company, and Northern Pacific Railway), 1957 (Box-folder 16 / 7)
    - Archer S. Taylor correspondence (includes Committee for Paradise Dam nominating committee material), 1957-1965 (Box-folder 16 / 8)
    - Television programs on dams, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 16 / 9)
    - L.P. "Cy" Tonner correspondence, 1957-1963 (Box-folder 16 / 10)
    - Treasurer's reports, 1957-1964 (Box-folder 16 / 11)
    - U.S. Army Corps of Engineers correspondence, 1948, 1957-1968 (Box-folder 16 / 12)
    - U.S. Army Corps of Engineers hearings, 1948, 1956-1959 (Box-folder 16 / 13-15)
    - U.S. Army Corps of Engineers reports, 1958-1960 (Box-folder 16 / 16)
    - U.S. Bonneville Power Administration (includes correspondence, rate plans, speeches, generation and sales statistics, news releases, contracts), 1946-1967 (Box-folder 17 / 1-3)
    - U.S. Bonneville Power Administration Advisory Council, 1961-1963 (Box-folder 17 / 4-6)
    - U.S. Bonneville Power Administration Advisory Council, 1962-1964 (Box-folder 18 / 1-2)
    - U.S. Bonneville Power Administration spot rate maps (compares price of electricity in various Montana, Idaho, Washington, and Oregon locations), 1964, undated (Box-folder 18 / 3)
    - U.S. Congressional correspondence, 1957-1960 (Box-folder 18 / 4)
    - U.S. Senate Select Committee on Water Resources (includes bills, resolutions, correspondence, hearing testimony of Committee for Paradise Dam, G.M. Brandborg, Leonard Kenfield, and Fred E. Buck), 1959-1960 (Box-folder 18 / 5)
    - Upper Columbia Development Council (opposed to Paradise Dam), 1957-1964 (Box-folder 18 / 6)
    - Upstream Storage Committee of Northwest Public Power Association minutes, 1959 (Box-folder 18 / 7)
    - Water crop value, 1962 (Box-folder 18 / 8)
    - Water Resources Planning Act (S.2246: includes testimony, 1961 (Box-folder 18 / 9)
    - Robert C. Weller correspondence (Lumber and Sawmill Workers Union), 1957-1966 (Box-folder 18 / 10)
  - Clippings
    - Flathead Courier, 1957-1961 (Box-folder 19 / 1)
    - Hungry Horse News, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 19 / 2)
    - People's Voice, 1957-1961 (Box-folder 19 / 3)
    - Plainsman, 1956-1958 (Box-folder 19 / 4)
    - Ronan Pioneer, 1957-1961 (Box-folder 19 / 5)
    - St. Ignatius Post, 1957 (Box-folder 19 / 6)
    - Miscellaneous, 1949, 1957-1960 (Box-folder 19 / 7-12)
    - Miscellaneous, 1961-1969, undated (Box-folder 20 / 1-10)
  - Hearings
    - Hungry Horse Dam hearing (includes testimony by J.E. Corette of Montana Power Company), 1947-1949 (Box-folder 21 / 1)
    - Paradise Dam hearing, Missoula (includes resolutions of support by large number of organizations), 1957 (Box-folder 21 / 2-3)
    - Paradise Dam hearing, Helena, 1957 (Box-folder 21 / 4)
    - Paradise Dam hearings (related material), 1957 (Box-folder 21 / 5)
    - Columbia River Report hearings (includes testimony of National Hells Canyon Association, Roy F. Bessey, Paul K. Harlow), March 1959 (Box-folder 21 / 6)
    - U.S. Senate Select Committee on Water Resources hearing (testimony of Frances Logan), October 1959 (Box-folder 21 / 7)
    - U.S. Senate hearing on S. 1226 (includes testimony of Frances Logan, S.R. Logan, Howard Zahniser of The Wilderness Society, David R. Brower of Sierra Club, Gus Norwood of Northwest Public Power Association), December 1959 (Box-folder 21 / 8)
    - U.S. Senate hearing on S. 1226 (includes correspondence and related material), December 1959 (Box-folder 22 / 1-3)
    - Montana H.B. 217 and H.R. 8 hearing (includes testimony of Gus Norwood of Northwest Public Power Association, R.E. Corette; also includes text of bill and resolution), 1959 (Box-folder 22 / 4-5)
    - U.S. Senate S. 1226 hearing (correspondence and related material), 1960 (Box-folder 22 / 6)
    - U.S. Senate S. 1226 hearing (correspondence and related material), 1960 (Box-folder 23 / 1-2)